Alan Freed Collection ARC.0006
Library and Archives
- Series III: Publications, 1939-1992
  - Magazines, 1988, 1992
    - Kicks, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 58, Object 1)
    - Kicks, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 58, Object 2)
  - Sheet Music, 1954-1957, 1982
    - "Sincerely" by Harvey Fuqua and Alan Freed, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 59, Object 1)
    - "Sincerely" by Harvey Fuqua and Alan Freed, circa 1954 (Box 1, Folder 59, Object 2)
    - "Mabellene" by Chuck Berry, Russ Frato, and Alan Freed, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 59, Object 3)
    - "Most Of All" by Harvey Fuqua and Alan Freed, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 59, Object 4)
    - "The Rock And Roll Waltz" by Shorty Allen and Dick Ware, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 59, Object 5)
    - "Teenage Meeting (Gonna Rock It Up Right)" by Julius Dixon, Ollie Jones, and Alan Freed, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 59, Object 6)
    - "The Verdict" by Glen Moore and Alan Freed, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 59, Object 7)
    - Alan Freed's Rock And Roll Party, circa 1955 (Box 1, Folder 59, Object 8)
    - "Country Dance" by Ollie Jones, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 59, Object 9)
    - "Giddy-Up-A Ding Dong" by Freddie Bell and Pep Lattanzi, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 59, Object 10)
    - "Your Love Is My Love" by Francis Edwards, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 59, Object 11)
    - "Kiddio" by Brook Benton and Clyde Otis, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 59, Object 12)
    - "Sincerely" by Harvey Fuqua and Alan Freed, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 59, Object 13)
  - Yearbook - The Quaker Annual, 1940
    - 1939 (Box 1, Folder 60, Object 1)
    - 1940 (Box 1, Folder 61, Object 1)
      A2010.1.12
      Item on exhibit. Consult the Library and Archives staff in advance of your visit for additional information.
    - Page 25 photocopy, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 61, Object 2-3)
- Series IV: Ephemera, 1955-1961, 1978
  Series IV: Ephemera contains materials related to Alan Freed and his live appearances and films, including advertisements, photographs, posters, press books, programs, and tickets. The materials are arranged by type and then chronologically. Oversize materials are stored out of sequence due to size and condition concerns.
  - Advertisements, 1957, 1961
    - Coral Records/"Atomic!" Alan Freed - Page 46 of The Billboard Music-Record Programming Guide, 1957 November 11 (Drawer-folder FF.1.8-1, Object 27)
    - Photocopy of plaque-mounted promotional photo from Cash Box Magazine of Alan Freed, Ral Donnor, George Goldner for Gone-End record label, 1961 December 16 (Box 2, Folder 1, Object 1)
      Existence and Location of Originals
      The original plaque is in the care of the Rock and Roll Hall of Fame & Museum.
  - Belgian posters (22”x 14”), 1956-1957
    - Rock Around the Clock, 1956 (Drawer-folder FF.1.8-1, Object 8)
      A2010.1.18
    - Mister Rock and Roll, 1957 (Drawer-folder FF.1.8-1, Object 9)
  - Cast and credits, 1956, 1978
    - Don't Knock The Rock, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 2, Object 1)
  - Color separations, 1978
    - American Hot Wax - front/back of gatefold LP cover, 1978 (Drawer-folder FF.1.8-2, Object 1)
    - American Hot Wax - inside of gatefold LP cover, 1978 (Drawer-folder FF.1.8-2, Object 2)
  - Concert posters, 1958 April 25
    - Big Beat - Minneapolis Municipal Auditorium [reproduction], 1958 April 25 (Drawer-folder FF.1.8-1, Object 28)
  - Half-Sheets (22” x 28”), 1956-1957
    - Rock, Rock, Rock!, 1956 (Drawer-folder FF.1.8-1, Object 3)
    - Don't Knock the Rock [Style A], 1956 (Drawer-folder FF.1.8-1, Object 4)
    - Don't Knock the Rock [Style B], 1956 (Drawer-folder FF.1.8-1, Object 5)
    - Mister Rock and Roll [Style A], 1957 (Drawer-folder FF.1.8-1, Object 6)
    - Mister Rock and Roll [Style B], 1957 (Drawer-folder FF.1.8-1, Object 7)
  - Inserts (36” x 14”), 1956-1957
    - Rock Around the Clock, 1956 (Drawer-folder FF.1.8-1, Object 17)
    - Rock, Rock, Rock!, 1956 (Drawer-folder FF.1.8-1, Object 18)
    - Don't Knock the Rock, 1956 (Drawer-folder FF.1.8-1, Object 19)
    - Mister Rock and Roll, 1957 (Drawer-folder FF.1.8-1, Object 20)
      A2010.1.17
  - Lobby cards (11” x 14”), 1956-1957, 1959
    - Rock Around the Clock, 1956 (Drawer-folder FF.1.8-1, Object 32)
    - Rock, Rock, Rock! [Title Card], 1956 (Drawer-folder FF.1.8-1, Object 33)
    - Don't Knock the Rock [Title Card], 1956 (Drawer-folder FF.1.8-1, Object 34)
    - Don't Knock the Rock [#2], 1956 (Drawer-folder FF.1.8-1, Object 35)
    - Don't Knock the Rock [#3], 1956 (Drawer-folder FF.1.8-1, Object 36)
    - Don't Knock the Rock [#4], 1956 (Drawer-folder FF.1.8-1, Object 37)
    - Don't Knock the Rock [#5], 1956 (Drawer-folder FF.1.8-1, Object 38)
    - Don't Knock the Rock [#6], 1956 (Drawer-folder FF.1.8-1, Object 39)
    - Don't Knock the Rock [#7], 1956 (Drawer-folder FF.1.8-1, Object 40)
    - Don't Knock the Rock [#8], 1956 (Drawer-folder FF.1.8-1, Object 41)
    - Mister Rock and Roll [#5], 1957 (Drawer-folder FF.1.8-1, Object 42)
    - Go, Johnny Go!, 1959 (Drawer-folder FF.1.8-1, Object 43-44)
  - Mexican lobby cards (14” x 17”), 1956-1957
    - Rock, Rock, Rock! ( Bambole Frenetico), 1956 (Drawer-folder FF.1.8-1, Object 29)
      A2010.1.20
    - Mister Rock and Roll ( Los Freneticos), 1957 (Drawer-folder FF.1.8-1, Object 30-31)
      Object 31: A2010.1.21
      Object 31 on exhibit. Consult the Library and Archives staff in advance of your visit for additional information.
  - One-Sheets (41” x 27”), 1956, 1978
    - Rock, Rock, Rock!, 1956 (Drawer-folder FF.1.8-1, Object 1)
      A2010.1.2
    - American Hot Wax, 1978 (Drawer-folder FF.1.8-1, Object 2)
  - Photographs, 1955
    - Brooklyn Paramount Theatre marquee, 1955 (Drawer-folder FF.1.8-1, Object 26)
      A2010.1.3
  - Pressbooks, 1978
    - Rock, Rock, Rock!, 1956 (Drawer-folder FF.1.8-1, Object 22)
    - Don't Knock The Rock/ Rumble On The Docks, 1956 (Drawer-folder FF.1.8-1, Object 23)
    - Mister Rock and Roll, 1957 (Drawer-folder FF.1.8-1, Object 24)
    - Go, Johnny, Go!, 1959 (Drawer-folder FF.1.8-1, Object 25)
    - American Hot Wax, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 3, Object 1)
  - Programs, 1955-1957
    - Alan Freed and His "Rock 'N Roll" Easter Jubilee, 1955 April (Box 2, Folder 4, Object 1)
    - Alan Freed and His "Rock 'N Roll" Holiday Jubilee, 1955 December (Box 2, Folder 4, Object 2)
    - Alan Freed's Easter Jubilee of Stars, 1956 April (Box 2, Folder 4, Object 3)
    - Alan Freed Rock ‘N Roll Second Anniversary, 1956 September (Box 2, Folder 4, Object 4)
      A2010.1.6
    - Alan Freed Christmas Jubilee, 1956 December (Box 2, Folder 4, Object 5)
    - Alan Freed Holiday Jubilee, 1957 February (Box 2, Folder 4, Object 6)
    - Alan Freed's Summer Festival, 1957 July (Box 2, Folder 4, Object 7)
    - Alan Freed's Third Anniversary Show, 1957 September (Box 2, Folder 4, Object 8)
    - Alan Freed Christmas Jubilee, 1957 December (Box 2, Folder 4, Object 9)
  - Programs, 1958-1959, 1978
    - Alan Freed Presents The Big Beat, 1958 April (Box 2, Folder 5, Object 1)
    - Alan Freed Presents The Big Beat, 1958 September (Box 2, Folder 5, Object 2)
    - Alan Freed’s Christmas Jubilee, 1958 December (Box 2, Folder 5, Object 3)
    - Alan Freed's Easter Jubilee, 1959 April (Box 2, Folder 5, Object 4)
    - Alan Freed's Fifth Anniversary Show, 1959 September (Box 2, Folder 5, Object 5)
    - Alan Freed's Christmas Jubilee, 1959 December (Box 2, Folder 5, Object 6)
  - Promotional cards, 1978
    - American Hot Wax (Drawer-folder FF.1.8-1, Object 21, Box 2, Folder 6, Object 1)
  - Stamford, Connecticut Phone Directory, 1957
    - Page 505/506 (Box 2, Folder 7, Object 1)
  - Three-Sheets (81” x 41”), 1957
    - Mister Rock and Roll, 1957 (Tube-object 2-1)
  - Tickets, 1959 October 22
    - Allan Freed's "Big Beat Party" invitation, 1959 October 22 (Box 2, Folder 8, Object 1)
  - Window cards (22” x 14”), 1956-1957
    - Don't Knock the Rock, 1956 (Drawer-folder FF.1.8-1, Object 10)
    - Don't Knock the Rock (Melrose Theatre), 1956 (Drawer-folder FF.1.8-1, Object 11)
    - Don't Knock the Rock (Sam Davis Theatre), 1956 (Drawer-folder FF.1.8-1, Object 12)
    - Don't Knock the Rock, 1956; Trimmed. (Drawer-folder FF.1.8-1, Object 13)
      A2010.1.19
    - Mister Rock and Roll, 1957 (Drawer-folder FF.1.8-1, Object 14)
    - Mister Rock and Roll (New Years Eve Midnight Show), 1957 (Drawer-folder FF.1.8-1, Object 15)
      A2010.1.4
    - Mister Rock and Roll, 1957 (Drawer-folder FF.1.8-1, Object 16)
- Series V: Personal Papers [RESTRICTED], Bulk, 1940-1965; 1921-1965
  Some of the materials in this series are confidential and are, therefore, RESTRICTED. Redacted access copies of the confidential documents are available in the collection.
  Series V: Personal Papers [RESTRICTED] contains documents pertaining to the life, employment, and death of Alan Freed, including birth and death certificates, and his pathology report. The materials are arranged chronologically.
  - Freed, Albert James Certification of Birth (photocopy), 1921 December 20 (Box 2, Folder 9, Object 1)
  - Freed, Albert J. Certification of Military Service, 1941 May 16 (Box 2, Folder 9, Object 6)
  - Freed, Albert J. Personnel Employment Record [RESTRICTED], circa 1942 (Box 2, Folder 9, Object 2, Box 5, Folder 2, Object 1)
    This item is confidential and is, therefore, RESTRICTED. A redacted access copy of this confidential document is available in the collection.
  - Freed, Albert James and Betty Lou Bean marriage license (photocopy), 1943 August 14 (Box 2, Folder 9, Object 3)
  - Freed, Alan Certificate of Death (photocopy), 1965 January 20 (Box 2, Folder 9, Object 4)
  - Freed, Alan Pathological Report (photocopy), 1965 January 21 (Box 2, Folder 9, Object 5)
- Series VI: Audiovisual Materials [RESTRICTED], 1959, 1978, undated
  Series VI: Audiovisual Materials contains materials related to Alan Freed and his career, including an 8-track audiocassette soundtrack from a film based on his life, and a videotape of The Big Beat with Bobby Darin as host.
  Some of the audiovisual materials in this series are on defunct media formats and, therefore, are RESTRICTED. Access copies of these materials will have to be created prior to use. Consult the Library and Archives staff in advance of your visit to ensure access to these materials is available.
  An audiocassette, videocassette, various singles, and LPs have been transferred to the library collection. Please search for the "Alan Freed Collection" in the library catalog for a list of donated titles.
  - 8-track audiocassette, American Hot Wax [RESTRICTED], 1978 (Box 3, Object 1)
    This audiovisual material is on a defunct media formats and, therefore, is RESTRICTED. An access copy of this materials will have to be created prior to use. Consult the Library and Archives staff in advance of your visit to ensure access to these materials is available.
  - VHS videocassette, The Big Beat with Bobby Darin as host, 1959 July 17 (Box 3, Object 2)
    The condition of this item has not yet been determined for playback purposes. An access copy of this item may have to be created prior to use. Consult the Library and Archives staff in advance of your visit to ensure access to this item is available.
- Series VII: 2011 Accruals [RESTRICTED], 1918-1978, 1999
  Series VII: 2011 [RESTRICTED] contains documents, magazines, and photographs pertaining to the life, employment, and death of Alan Freed, including birth and death certificates, his pathology report, high school yearbooks, and the accounting from one of his films. The materials are arranged alphabetically by type, then chronologically.
  The materials in this series are CLOSED until a signed gift agreement can be secured from the donor. Some of the materials in the collection are confidential and are, therefore, RESTRICTED. Consult the Library and Archives staff in advance of your visit to ensure access to these materials is available.
  - ABC Advertising and Promotion Department audience promotion presskit with photographs, 1957 May 4 (Box 4, Folder 1, Object 1)
  - American Hot Wax, 1977-1978
    - Cast and credit, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 2, Object 1)
    - Promotional cards, 1978 (Drawer-folder FF.1.8-3, Object 3)
    - Reproduction of Alan Freed and his "Rock 'N Roll Holiday Jubilee", 1978 (Box 4, Folder 2, Object 2)
    - Script - second draft, 1977 October 26 (Box 4, Folder 3, Object 1)
    - Soundtrack album magazine advertisement, 1978 (Drawer-folder FF.1.8-3, Object 1)
    - Promotional photographs, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 2, Object 2-5)
  - Brass Rail dinner menu and wine list, 1948 January 23 (Box 4, Folder 4, Object 1)
  - Don't Knock The Rock cast and credits, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 5, Object 1)
  - KNOB-FM folder, circa 1965 (Drawer-folder FF.1.8-3, Object 2)
    Last station to employ Alan Freed.
  - LCL Productions, Incorporated correspondence from Lew Platt to Glenn, 1955 June 6 (Box 4, Folder 6, Object 1)
  - Mister Rock and Roll Paramount Pictures Corporation cumulative statement of account with Aurora Productions, Incorporated, 1958 June 28 (Box 4, Folder 7, Object 1)
  - 1950s - Celebrate the Century United States postage stamps, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 8, Object 1)
  - Magazines, 1956-1957
    - Teenage Rock and Roll Review, 1956 October (Box 4, Folder 9, Object 1)
    - "Rock 'N' Roll -- Music." TV Guide [Cleveland Edition], 1957 May 4-10 (Box 4, Folder 9, Object 2)
    - Irwin, Theodore. "Rock 'n Roll 'n Alan Freed." Pageant, 1957 July (Box 4, Folder 9, Object 3)
  - Magazines, 1958-1959
    - Behrman, Anita. “What Alan Freed Really Thinks About Rock ‘n’ Roll.” People Today, 1958 October (Box 4, Folder 10, Object 1)
    - Bolstad, Helen. "The Big Sound For 1959." TV Radio Mirror, 1958 November (Box 4, Folder 10, Object 2)
    - "Daddy of the Big Beat: Alan Freed." Hit Parader, 1958 December (Box 4, Folder 10, Object 3)
    - "Show Business: Disc Jockeys: "Now Don't Cry." Time, 1959 December 7 (Box 4, Folder 10, Object 4)
  - Personal Papers, 1941, 1959-1965
    - Freed, Albert J. Certification of Military Service (photocopy), 1941 May 16 (Box 4, Folder 11, Object 1)
    - Freed, Alan certificate of appreciation, 1959 November 25 (Box 4, Folder 11, Object 2)
    - Freed, Alan Pathological Report (photocopy), 1965 January 21 (Box 4, Folder 11, Object 3)
  - Photographs, 1918-1964
    - Freed, Sr., Charles Sydney and Maude Palmer Freed, 1918 (Box 4, Folder 12, Object 1)
    - Freed, Alan, with note by Maude Freed on back, 1922, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 12, Object 16)
    - Freed, David, Alan Freed, and Charles Freed, Jr., circa 1930 (Box 4, Folder 12, Object 2)
    - Freed, Alan, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 12, Object 3)
    - Freed, Alan Salem High School senior picture with inscription on back, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 12, Object 4)
    - Parker, Jack, Alan Freed, Olive Mae (Bean) Parker, and unidentified on Alan and Betty Lou's wedding day in Columbiana County, Ohio, 1943 August 22 (Box 4, Folder 12, Object 5)
    - Freed, Alan with four unidentified people, ca. 1946 (Box 4, Folder 12, Object 17)
    - Freed, Alana, Alan Freed, Betty Lou Freed, and Lance Freed, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 12, Object 6)
    - Freed, Alan, circa 1950 (Box 4, Folder 12, Object 7)
    - Freed, Maude and Alan Freed, circa 1956 (Box 4, Folder 12, Object 8)
    - Flaming Hotel swimming pool, circa 1956 (Box 4, Folder 12, Object 9)
    - Freed, Lance and Alan Freed at Shippan Point rented house in Stamford, Connecticut, circa 1956 (Box 4, Folder 12, Object 10)
    - Freed, Alan and Inga Boling on the set of Go, Johnny Go!, 1958 April (Box 4, Folder 12, Object 11)
    - Freed's Palm Springs, California home, 1962 October 28 (Box 4, Folder 12, Object 12)
    - Freed, Alan, circa 1962 (Box 4, Folder 12, Object 13)
    - Freed, Inga Boling, Alan Freed, and Lance Freed at Palm Springs, California home, 1963 December (Box 4, Folder 12, Object 14)
    - Freed, Alan on roof of Palm Springs, California home, 1964 June 6 (Box 4, Folder 12, Object 15)
  - Postcards, circa 1955
    - Al & Dick's Steak House (Box 4, Folder 13, Object 1)
    - Castro, Frankie (Box 4, Folder 13, Object 2)
      Autographed.
  - Yearbook - Quaker Annual, 1937-1940
    - 1937 (Box 4, Folder 14, Object 1)
    - 1938 (Box 4, Folder 15, Object 1)
    - 1939 (Box 4, Folder 16, Object 1)
    - 1940 (Box 4, Folder 17, Object 1)